I met my wife in...
It was the late 70s at Yosemite National Park.
We got a cabin in the wintertime
and with a bunch of friends
and my little brother Wayne invited Patty
because they were friends and she was friends of his wife at the time.
And so they invited her up.
And that's the first time I met her.
And I heard that Patty said you didn't talk to her on the way back.
On the truck?
No, we didn't have much to say.
We were both tired,
but yeah, we didn't talk too much that day.
But then when I was in back down to Concord,
we ended up going out and started dating and that.
When did you decide to get married?
Her roommate said if I was going to hang around, I had to start paying rent or get out of the house."
So Patty said she was gonna get out of the house.
And then we were starting to look at renting or buying a house.
then I told her, " Well, let's just get married, too, and get it all done."
So that's what we did.
It doesn't sound very romantic.
It wasn't.
Practical, that's me, practical.
Can you share this story when you met father-in-law at the Chinese restaurant or something?
Well, I met him at the house,
but we all went out to dinner one night.
He liked his alcohol, so he was always pretty well looped.
And we were eating at a Szechuan Chinese place,
and he saw I had some Szechuan dish,
and I was pushing the peppers aside.
And he goes, " What are you doing?"
I said, " Those are peppers, they're hot. "
You're not gonna eat 'em?" I said no
and he was gonna show off I guess and he grabbed one and bit into it
he didn't like it because it was hot
and then he started drinking his drink milk water whatever was on the table
he'd never played with my food or talked about it again
because he'd he made a mistake on that one
because those peppers are hot
so do you have any other story with Patty's dad
Nothing that does. He comes out.
I mean, we went camping to Bucks Lake with him and her family.
And I always enjoyed being around him.
He'd always take me down to the bar here in town.
We'd come back drunk.
I'd have four or five drinks on the counter.
He was all done with his and I couldn't keep up with him.
Didn't even try.
But it was... Me and Wayne Hunter and Don and everybody got taken to the bar with him.
Always had to drink too much with he and his buddies.
Do you remember when Patty met your parents the very first time?
Um, not a specific date.
I know we invited her over.
I don't know if it was the first time or not, but one of the times in Lafayette when they still had the house there.
and we were going over for dinner.
It was pretty early in the relationship
and she made a lemon meringue pie
and we carried it all the way from Martinez to Lafayette
and I went around a corner and all the filling came out of the pie
and the meringue stayed there
so when you looked at it, it looked like a perfectly good pie
but all the filling was on the floorboard.
She wasn't very happy.
Well, it depends on the time of year.
In the summertime, you've got to get up early
and do everything that you want to do before it gets too warm.
And then in the afternoon, you sit on the porch and have a beer
and rest and listen to the creek,
take a nap or read a book.
But there's always stuff to do.
I mean, there's always buildings to repair.
In wintertime, I'm doing a lot of fires to burn up the... stuff that's on the ground.
So it's, there's never a dull moment. There's always something to do.
Like any house.
Maybe you can share the your latest project.
Well, we rebuilt the stairs,
the front stairs to the house.
I've got that pretty well done.
I hired a guy to help me on that.
We're going to have another guy come up and put new screws in the roof, in the middle roof, because they're backing out
and it's a pain so they're gonna replace them all.
So there's there's always things that have to be done.
Well we've had every animal that
we way back we had a porcupine right by the Wayne's house.
We've had skunks, we got raccoons,
we got there's a few possums,
there's a mountain lion, there's bear.
Patty and I saw bear here last summer.
in the afternoon just walking through the property.
We've had coyotes, we have river otters.
There's just all sorts of birds,
hawks and stuff.
So did you see the bear in person?
Yeah, it was in the afternoon.
It was surprising that the last time it was a mama bear and a fairly old cub.
And they just walked out of the woods and walked upstream
I don't know what forced her to move during the heat of the day but something disturbed her
so she was looking for new a new place to sit, hang out
because it was pretty warm that day
so you did you see the mountain lion in person too?
yes yeah we were sitting down to dinner
it was the older bridge
and I heard this noise on the bridge
I thought it was a dog running across the
And I looked down about the same time it looked up
and saw me in the window and it stopped,
turned around and ran back.
And it's like, wow, that was a mountain lion.
I mean, we've seen tracks and stuff.
there's been a lot of sightings in and around now.
So they're there.
Come up and help me. I need help.
You got a lot to learn how to take care of the place.
You've got to learn how to put it into freeze protection
and where everything is to shut the water off if you need it.
There's a lot to learn.
You and Matthew need to get up
and spend some time figuring out how to put things all the way
and lock it up and what processes it needs to be done
especially the freeze drain in the house
make sure that nothing freezes inside
the usual stuff you do in the mountains
yeah okay okay thank
learn how to run the backhoe!